[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
price Anda automation
tutorial as you all know I've already
published 35 YouTube videos covering
different topics of prentist tasa
automation Concepts so in my previous
session we learned about how can you
create modify and then how can you
manipulate the Excel range or Excel
workbook by using Excel engine in
triena so I would recommend you guys to
go through my previous lesson 35 before
you watch this
session this is our lesson 36 in terms
of overall tricentis TSA automation
Concepts and this is our lesson 21 one
in terms of Advanced Training so in this
lesson I'm going to cover how can we
calculate the row count and how can we
calculate the column count of an Excel
range within the Excel workbook which
means if you store enormous data Excel
sheet right and then how can we
calculate the number of rows of data
that is present in the Excel sheet and
then how can we calculate number of
columns of the data that is present in
the Excel sheet please do subscribe to
the channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank you now let us jump
onto the system and see how can we
calculate row and column count of your
Excel
workbook this is my
TSA so if you remember
correctly we have learned all these oper
operations in our previous session tbox
delete file tbox open work book tbox
create Excel worksheet and then tbox
Define excel range tbox Excel range
manipulation to modify the data tbox
close or save workbook right so now let
me create a new folder here I want to
create a new folder
called row
and column
count and then I'm going to create a new
test
case row column
count here I want to
copy some of the test steps as is from
my previous session okay I want to copy
open Excel workbook and then Define
excel work range
Excel
range and then I want to copy close
workbook copy all these steps and paste
in the new test
case okay now we have Define excel range
correct and then open Excel workbook so
let me just put it into chronical order
so here first I'm going to open Excel
workbook but in this case I don't want
to create a new I want to use an Excel
existing Excel workbook that we created
in my previous session that's why I'm
selecting create new as false so I want
to use the same workbook that we created
earlier so let me show that workbook
okay in this workbook we can see this is
this has almost like six rows and then
two columns right so let me close
this
the same I'm using here now let me copy
or let me create a new test step here so
let me add a new test tip called
tbox Excel range manipulation I want to
insert a new step for Excel range
manipulation and bring this prior to
closing the Excel
workbook and and here what is the range
name the range name is same as my
previous step I want to use the same
range
name right and I want to rename this as
row
count
calculation now I want to insert the
same step one more time Excel range
manipul
and bring this Excel range manipulation
again prior to closing your Excel
workbook and I want to define the same
Excel range because I'm calculating the
column count for the same Excel
range and
now for row count how can I calculate
the row count so you need to use the
method called for the web table I'm
talking about in the data table you need
not to enter any row and column as we
did in earlier session while
manipulating the data because we are not
manipulating the data here we are just
calculating the row count that's why you
just need to use the data table row here
I want to calculate the row count so
there is an inbuilt method called row
count call that inbuilt
method here R
count equal Al to I'm going to store it
into buffer called row
count I'll do one thing to differentiate
I'm going to call it as Excel row count
right and here the action mode should be
buffer need to store this into a buffer
called Excel row count in the same way
for column count
also I have another method called column
count
column count no space equal to
excel
column
count so here we are calculating the row
count and column count of this
particular Excel range that we defined
right now here also you need to change
into buffer so now let us understand the
flow first what we are doing we are
opening an Excel workbook which is an
existing workbook I'm not creating new
workbook and then we already defined the
Excel range for the particular work
book and then I am calculating the row
count in the Excel workbook and then I'm
calculating the column count I'm storing
them into buffer so that I can see the
value in the buffer and I can use that
buffer value for my future test case
automation
and I'm closing the workbook and I'm
saving the workbook while closing the
workbook so now let us save this and let
us run this particular test
case right click and
run it should calculate row and column
count of your Excel
workbook so let us see our test result
so if you see here your data table row
count is six correct and your column
count should be two and that should
store into a buffer called Excel column
count has been set to six same way Excel
row count has been set to
six and the column count has been set to
two right hope you all understand how
can you you perform row count and column
count for an Excel workbook by using
trient
to please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank
[Music]
you